NETWORK MANAGER

Career Overview

Passionate for using technology to solve business challenges. A result driven networking industry veteran of 16 years, experienced in designing, troubleshooting, and operating large enterprise and retail LAN/WAN networks.

Working as Infrastructure consultant for designing and integrating Network, Data Center, and Information Security solutions for customers across various industries. Being a trusted adviser for clients, proud of delivering solutions that drive business outcomes in an agile and elegant manner.

Qualifications

- CISCO Certified Network Associate (CCNA)
- Software Defined Network
- Cisco Technologies
- AWS Cloud

- Data Center Networking
- Strong Communication Skills
- · Result oriented
- Highly Analytical

Technical Skills

Routing Protocols - EIGRP, OSPF, BGP

First Hop Redundancy Protocols - HSRP, GLBP, VRRP

Multicast, STP, VTP, Virtual LAN

Cisco ASA; ACL; IPSec Tunnels

Cisco IOS, IOS-XE, NX-OS

MPLS, vrf-lite

Cisco Enterprise LAN Access Switches, LAN core, distribution class switches and Data Center class switches

F5 LTM/GTM

Cisco Branch routers, WAN aggregation and edge routers

Trained on Software Defined Networking - Cisco ACI and Nuage Networks

Trained on Amazon Web Services

Work Experience

Network Manager 11/2007 to Current Department Of Administrative Services, State Of Ohio Mcarthur, OH

Accenture is a leading consulting organization providing cutting edge technological solution services to its client. As a Infrastructure Consulting Manager I have worked across retail banking, energy, pharmaceutical and manufacturing industries to provide network technology expertise. In the various roles I have

- Design, Planned and Deployed Data Center Infrastructure at multiple locations in US and Singapore
- Responsible for large transformation project
- Lead team of on-shore and off-shore network engineers
- Conducted site readiness assessment for Data Center
- Provided architecture analysis to ensure requirements are scoped correctly
- · Provide assessment of LAN/WAN design and identify security gaps to provide best practices recommendations
- Worked with different vendors for solution scoping
- Mentored junior team members
- Conducted brown-bag sessions
- Acted as Level 3 escalation on network issues
- Ordered network equipments and circuits
- Created rack elevations, IP addressing plan, issue resolution/support and provide ops transition plan

Sr Network Engineer 03/2003 to 11/2007 Marco Technologies Eau Claire, WI

Corliant Inc a strategic partner for Cisco Systems provides network infrastructure, security, and convergence solutions to enterprises and service providers. Corliant Inc was acquired by Accenture LLP on Oct 2007. I have helped Service Providers, Financial Company and Leading Airlines customers in Japan, India, Belize, Suriname and US. For these clients I have helped

- Implement MPLS enabled IP backbone.
- Design IP addressing scheme.
- Design, develop and implement configurations for various devices.
- Configure and upgrade IOS on GSR's, 7200, Cat 4000 and Cat 6500 Cisco devices
- Provide Operational and Troubleshooting support to NOC
- Verify configuration on routers against best practices guidelines
- Pro-actively identify and modify the OSPF and BGP configuration inconsistency across the all the POP locations of the Service Provider
- Work on acceptance test and certification for the BTS
- Configuration and testing of Session Border Controllers
- Testing of various software and hardware related IOS features-MLPPP, OIR, QoS, eiBGP, VRF over FEC
- Identify the bugs and co-ordinate with TAC/DE for problem resolution

Sr Network Engineer 07/2002 to 03/2003 Marco Technologies Kansas City, MO

Siemens Information Systems Ltd. (SISL) is a leading "Systems Integrator and Total Solutions Provider" offering high-end consultancy It provides single-source solutions and services. My role was to provide

- Provide Presales/Post sales Support to Various Networking Clients
- Created business model for NOC and DC setup

Network Executive 09/2001 to 07/2002 Aircell Chicago, IL

TISL is a Class A ISP providing spectrum of services catering to the various needs of leading corporates in India. TISL provides IP based VPN solutions, Internet bandwidth and data hosting. I was part of network operations team

- Supporting day-to-day network operations
- Handling L2 escalations

Network Engineer 09/2000 to 08/2001 Aircell Broomfield, CO

CSSL is a leading provider of next-generation geospatial, networking and enterprise IT solutions. As a Network Engineer, I supported internal and client LAN and WAN networks

Network Engineer 12/1999 to 09/2000 Avantus Houlton, ME

CCIPL was the business partners of Motorola Multi service Networking Division for India and SAARC countries. As Network Engineer was, responsible for

· Implementing, updating and supporting Network Infrastructure including Motorola routers, switches and leased line moderns

Systems Engineer 08/1998 to 12/1999 Jetking City , STATE

Jetking is a premier institute for education in computer hardware and networking. As Systems Engineer was responsible for

- Design, implementation and maintenance of LAN
- Installation, configuration, administration and troubleshooting of servers, workstations and operating systems

Education and Training

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Engineering North Maharashtra University India

Diploma: Computer Technology Directorate of Technical Education India